How to ship in Zerodha or how to ship
in Zerodha, this is a very simple topic
but many people face some issues,
so I will
show you my Zerodha app here, so first of all
see, we have started this Zerodha app, in this you have to
click once in your tools area, if you click on
this tools area then
you will see three things above,
basket, ship and alert, in this you have to
go to the ship area, so I click on the ship area here, when
you do not have any ship then
you will see a blank here, nothing will be
shown, it will say no such ship and if there is
any other ship then you will see it listed here like this
and here
you will see this for create new SIP, if you
click here then nothing will happen,
see I am clicking but
for this you have to click, to
ship on this new SIP you have a little
process, you have to understand that, so here
you have to do a  If you want to ship to one city,
or a picnic in two cities, or a
picnic in three cities, you have to create a basket.
I'll
show you how that happens on the screen. After that,
you have to select a date. Whether you want to
ship once a month,
twice a month, or
as many times as you want, you
can do this up to five times. You select the date
and then activate the shipment. So,
look,
I click on "New Ship" here. For example,
I
want to deposit money into all three banks: HDFC Bank,
ICICI Bank, and SBI Bank
every month, on the 2nd of every month.
Now, for this, I have to do some work. So,
I can name the shipment anything here. If
I want to deposit money into three banks,
I'll
name it. Okay, so you
can name it anything you want,
but I'll remember that this is happening in these three
banks. Now, to ship.  The
important thing that I told you is that
you have to create a basket, so
if this basket is already created for you then it is
fine, if it is not created then we will click on it,
New Basket and whatever name you
want to give it, I will call it, Late
Free Bank Basket, okay,
three banks are added in it, if you want
you can add the names of the banks by ICC,
but I have created a Three Bank Basket and now
this is my basket creation page,
see here you can see the names,
you can add up to 20 items in it,
right now there is no item in it,
to add an item,
we will search by clicking on this point here, okay, so
I clicked on this, first of all take it,
I added HDFC Bank, okay,
now this is HDFC Bank, in this we have to buy and
not sell, so we
added Buy, now see the important point here,
see these are two things, these are two more things,
you should understand, there is nothing in the ship of all these, so do
not select them,
first of all, always keep the long term
selected, select intraday.  Don't do this
because if you select intraday, it will be
bought on that day but
Zerodha will automatically exit at 3:20 in the evening, so
select this, always select long term
because you
want to invest for the long term. Second is market
price versus limit price, always
keep the market price in it, never select the limit price
because what is the issue in limit price,
today you have to pay the
price here in the limit price, now
if you pay this price and if the
price goes above that in the future, then you will
never get these shares in a lot, so that is why
you should always keep
this market selected here, if
not limit then I place this market order,
market order means that if
I have selected the market then
I do not have the option to enter the price, whatever will be the
best possible price in the market at that time,
you will be allotted shares on that, so
these two important things are market and long
term, you should keep these in each, so I have
just shown you in one quantity for example,
I have added this one  The
quantity is of HDFC and after this I
click on the search one,
here I am searching for ICC Bank,
I added it as well, a quantity and
here I again selected the long term market and kept
adding it,
friends this is not being bought at all, it is
only being added, meaning you are not buying it right now, it will be
bought when you start the ship, so keep that in mind, the
third SBI, then we add
SBI N,
we have added this, clicked on buy from
long term market and we have added this also, it has
not been bought, now see, now it is
showing the required margin for this, that is,
how much money will be required and this
final margin is normally for those who
trade in futures and options, for
you if you are looking to invest in shares in the long term
or in ET
like Nifty Vijay, then both these
things will be visible to you from both,
so you can simply say
that brother, in that, if this
trade is sent today at this time, then a trade of Rs 3270 will be done
now  You might
want to see how much ₹1600 is going into this,
how much ₹900 is going into this,
how much ₹500 is going into this, so less is going into this, so if
you want, I will modify its quantity by increasing it
and
take this quantity, I made it three, okay,
I made its quantity three,
I increased its quantity to two, like this, now
whatever quantity you want to keep, now
I have set the quantity, now the
Kalasan trade will go in this, the 1921
trade will go in this, and the 1700 trade will go in this,
so roughly the EM in all three was that
almost equal amount of money goes into all three, so
now my EM is 5362,
but keep in mind that if this share price goes down, then
this amount will also go down monthly,
but if this share price goes up, then
this amount will also go up monthly, so in
this way you can create your own basket,
now after creating the basket, you will
not have to click on the execute button.  You have to press this,
I will also say for Zerodha, that
after this basket is created, actually press the
execute button. Many people make this mistake.
If you move this execute
button from here to here, your
order will be executed immediately. So you don't have to do this.
Friends, keep in mind that your basket is
created. Now you have to go back with this back button.
Now
look at your basket, it is created.
Okay, so now you have to select this basket.
Okay, so now it has been shipped.
Okay, now if you want to create any other basket,
suppose I have
created a basket of three banks. Now,
suppose you want to invest in three IT companies, Infosys,
TCS and Kaltech, then you
can create a new basket again. I am not creating one,
but you can still create one if you want.
Okay, so your basket is created. Now
after this, what is below is your schedule, on
which date and
how many times every month you want to invest and ship this money. So,
like I did,
I had said that on the 2nd of every month, that is, the
second date of every month,
see, you can also select the date and at
what time, so I go to our
Indian stock market, that band is at 3:3, so a
little earlier than that, that is, at
3:00 pm, this
investment should be done on the 2nd and the same amount should be invested again on the 16th, so
I have to do it twice, so I clicked on this ad
and once again I clicked on the ad here
and instead of the first, I
selected 16 and I kept the time the same as
3:00 pm, so now this will be my
investment twice every month, you do not have to do it twice, you have to do it only once,
so you
can delete one, so right now your
investment is the name of the ship of three banks, in that a
basket of one bank has been
created, the investment of three banks is approximately Rs. 5300,
that amount is not fixed, keep in
mind that the amount can go up or down,
but you will get one share of HDFC, two of ICC
and three of SBI,
whatever the price will be on that date.  It will definitely be purchased
and it must have been purchased at 3:00 pm.
Okay, so this has become your ship. Now
if you create this ship,
your ship has now been activated, which means that on the next 2nd,
money will automatically be deducted from your Zerodha account. This is the active status. Okay, there may be
some other changes in this, but I will
tell you about it, but understand that right now this is an
active status, which means that as soon as the 2nd of the next month
comes, this much money will be
deducted from your Zerodha account and these six shares will be transferred
to your DP account.
But if your money decreases or does
not increase on that day, then it is possible that the ship may fail. So keep in
mind that on the 2nd, there should be
money in your account. Okay, now
after this we will see that suppose
in some month you do not have money and
you cannot pay in it, then what can you do for that, you can pause it.
Look, it has been paused. Now you can
see this status, this pause, which means that
until you do not activate it again, even if the
2nd date passes, your ship will still be there.
If there is some cash employee or something like this has happened, then
you can pause it. Okay, so
this is positive. Whenever you want to
reactivate it, you can click on it again
and resume it, then it becomes
active again. In this way, you
can create a new ship at any time, you can pause it.
And when your work is over, or if that's all it takes,
and
I don't have to do anything else, then
look below, there is a delete ship button.
You can delete this IP whenever you want. If
you delete the CIP, then
after that, whatever has been created after that date will be
fine, but no more ships will be created in the future.
You have the option to edit,
you have the option to pause, you have the
option to delete. So, right now I am going to keep this ship
active, so I will
leave it like this. Okay, so
friends, in this way, friends, you can easily create any
number of shares you want in Zerodha every month,
twice a month, thrice a month, whatever you
want. You can create your own systematic investment
plan and do it.  can thank
you